

NATASHA LAMING

A creative, engaging strategic planner with a passion for learning, a collaborative approach and 20 years' experience influencing business and brand strategy through the application of commercial and human insight. My work is motivated by 3 driving passions:

- · To understand what really makes people tick
- To find new ways to get to better insight
- To enjoy the journey and the team, as much as delivering the solution

I am genuinely excited by great ideas - whether using those of others or creating fresh new ones – and applying them to solve real world problems. I strive for the next "aha" moment when the key to unlocking the problem becomes clear and am at my most motivated working in true partnerships with businesses and brands that seek to make the world better in some way.

CORE SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Strategic Planning

As my career has developed, I have naturally evolved from researcher to strategic planner, spending more time advising senior teams on the implications of new insight and facilitating exciting new strategies with the help of a tried and tested set of skills and tools:

- strong facilitation skills to harvest the ideas and insight lying hidden within a team or organisation
- fluency in a broad variety of tools, templates and models that aid the creation of powerful brand positioning, architecture and comms plans
- creative problem-solving ability to look outside the usual sources of reference and reframe the problem to get to new perspectives and exciting solutions
- a rare mix of creative, big picture and critical analytical thinking skills to bring together inspiring brand vision with a solid commercial case

Research Management

I have held both agency and client-side roles, designing and delivering impactful research programmes locally and at an international level for a broad spectrum of well-loved household names and dynamic challenger brands. This has afforded me

- a comprehensive knowledge of a breadth of qualitative and quantitative research methodologies and a strong sense of best practice across the industry
- a highly effective and trusted network of fellow research professionals
- a solid grasp of how to write effective briefs and deliver inspiring debriefs that get to the heart of the issue and really drive change
- strong time and budget management discipline
- flexibility and pragmatism in problem solving

Leadership & Influence

My leadership style is collaborative and based on trust and positive challenge. I seek to persuade by actively involving stakeholders, sharing my passion and projecting an inspiring vision of what could be. Effectiveness of this approach is borne out by

- · a proven ability to deliver game-changing projects
- comfort communicating opinions and recommendations at the highest level
- success in coaching and training others in core research and creative thinking skills
- my election by marketing colleagues to represent and support them through organizational change

CAREER SUMMARY

TEAM ELEVEN

Strategist Apr 2018 – Apr 2021

A strategic planner in a young, fast-growing, full-service marketing agency. I was instrumental in building a best in class strategy team including the development of consumer research capability within the agency that allowed us to bring more value and better solutions to our clients, further upstream.

Main achievements:

- I built a new insight consultancy arm to the agency which delivered £0.5m additional revenue in its first full year of operation and provided the fundamental insight that set the long term strategic direction for a portfolio of client brands.
- I coached strategy team to up their game on strategic workshop delivery and facilitation
- I consulted on and created an inspiring agency culture that brought to life the companies values and behaviours to ensure engaged, satisfied, cohesive team through a time of fast growth

DANONE NUTRICIA ELN

Strategy & Insight Manager

Nov 2011 - Dec 2016

A marketing leadership role in the UKs largest infant nutrition business. As strategy and insight partner to the Cow & Gate brand team I had a real impact on the rejuvenation of one of the UKs most trusted heritage brands. Latterly, I have been instrumental in kick-starting the innovation process which will be critical to the future growth of the business. Main achievements:

- I designed and implemented a high profile, game-changing UK innovation initiative that smashed every success target and delivered 6 high potential (top 20%) NPD concepts in year 1
- I was instrumental in delivering an extensive relaunch for C&G; both as a thinking
 partner to the brand director in defining the brand mission and communication
 strategy and by providing insight to inspire, develop and validate the creative work of
 pack design and comms agencies. Relaunch returned the brand to growth (2% YOY)
 after a period of decline and consideration grew from 28-35% after 6 months
- I reinvented an HCP Tracking Tool which enabled the Medical arm of the business to objectively assess performance against strategic priorities for the first time
- I delivered key elements of an innovative learning programme designed to boost consumer closeness and enrich the fundamental skills and confidence of the marketing team
- I was elected by my colleagues to represent them through the consultation process

BEAM GLOBAL SPIRITS & WINE

Senior Manager, Global Marketplace Insights

Jun 2007 – Nov 2009

A global management role; working at the heart of a newly formed global brands marketing team to manage the luxury spirits portfolio research and embed the vision of 'building brands that stir people'

Main achievements:

- I led a collaborative learning project across 4 key markets to create a new global brand DNA for Courvoisier.
- I persuaded the Global Marketing Director to significantly redefine Courvoisier's 'luxury' strategy for key markets
- I established the first global consumer trends programme for the business
- I was part of the team that delivered the BOOM! workshop to establish a new suite of brand building tools among the global marketing team

Within a small project team I co-built and rolled out a 10-market global brand tracker

ALLIED DOMECQ UK

Senior Insight Executive / Insight Manager

Jun 2002 – Jun 2007

Over 5 years I grew from an eager research exec in my first client-side role; partnering with brand teams and managing a wide range of research projects across a broad portfolio of brands, to eventually head up the UK insight function providing actionable consumer, shopper and competitor insight to all business teams.

Main achievements:

- I delivered a £1m shopper research project which established shopper insight as a competitive advantage, drove significant media coverage and ultimately led to 2 new category partnerships
- I led the UK management team in developing a 3yr UK Market Strategy
- I rolled out a Needstates Segmentation across UK business via functional workshops

TAYLOR NELSON SOFRES

Project Manager, Custom Solutions

Jun 1999 – Jun 2002

Working at the head office of Europe's largest marketing research company, my small team provided added value integrated research solutions to clients within the food and drink, fashion and entertainment industries. As a team we cooperatively met revenue & profit targets which increased 20-40% year on year for the duration.

EDUCATION

BTEC Foundation in Art & Design, City College Brighton & Hove 2012

Postgraduate Foundation in Marketing, **University of Liverpool**1998

BSc Psychology and Sociology, University of Bath

Including placement year at **Harvard University Graduate School of Education Upton High School**

1986-93
A Levels: Psychology (B), General Studies (B), Business Studies (C) and English

Lang (D)

GCSEs: 10 grade A - C including English (A) and Mathematics (A)